Guide to the Forrest Lee Dimmick papers, 1911-1968
Dimmick, Forrest Lee papers, 1911-1968
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Forrest Lee Dimmick papers, 1911-1968
2862
Forrest Lee Dimmick
7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, printed materials, publications, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers include correspondence with Karl M. Dallenbach, Edwin G. Boring, and other participants from the Inter-Society Color Council.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Psychologist. Forrest Lee Dimmick, Cornell University Class of 1915, Ph.D. 1920, was a psychologist and a professor at the University of Michigan, 1921-1925. He taught at Hobart College from 1925-1947, and was head of the Vision Branch of the Naval Medical Research Laboratory, Groton, Connecticut, 1947-1963.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers include correspondence with Karl M. Dallenbach, Edwin G. Boring, and other participants from the Inter-Society Color Council concerning his research in vision, particularly color vision, night vision, visual acuity, and color aptitude testing; newsletters, color swatches, and testing materials concerning his work (1940+) with Carl Foss and other members of the Inter-Society Color Council on the development of the Color Aptitude Test (CAT), a project sponsored by the Federation of Societies for Paint Technology; correspondence, minutes and pamphlets, 1955-1967, concerning the work that Dimmick, Foss, and Deane B. Judd did as members of the Committee on Uniform Color Scales of the Optical Society of America and for the National Bureau of Standards; correspondence, notes, and reports, 1964-1967, concerning his retirement activities as a consultant for the Biological Science Communications Project; papers concerning Dimmick's color specifications research based on "Just Noticeable Differences of Hue;" papers concerning his biographical research on his former professor, Edward Bradford Titchener; letters from Titchener to Dimmick and Mrs. Dimmick; recorded interview with Harry P. Weld, a Titchener colleague, and genealogical tables of the Titchener family. Personal papers include family letters; photographs; and other material belonging to Dimmick or his wife, Claire Comstock Dimmick.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Dimmick, Forrest Lee; Boring, Edwin Garrigues, 1886-1968.; Dallenbach, Karl M., 1887-1971.; Dimmick, Claire Comstock.; Foss, Carl.; Judd, Deane Brewster, 1900-1972.; Titchener, Edward Bradford, 1867-1927.; Weld, Harry Porter, 1877-1958.; Inter-Society Color Council.; Federation of Societies for Paint Technology.; Biological Science Communications Projects.
Subjects:
Color vision.; Color Psychological aspects.; Education.; Psychology, Experimental.; Psychology Research.; Psychology Study and teaching.; Genealogies.; Photoprints.; Psychologists. lsch
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Publications written and edited by Forrest Lee Dimmick
Series II. Publications by fellow researchers covering a wide area of subjects
Series III. CAT (Color Aptitude Test) and C.I.E. (Commission International Éclairage) research items
Series IV: Inter-Society Color Council
Series V: Optical Society of America (OSA)
Series VI: Personal Activities
Series VII: Correspondence
Series VIII: Personal memorabilia
Series IX: Mrs. Claire Comstock Dimmick, Ph.D. '20
Series X: Additional material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Publications written and edited by Forrest Lee Dimmick
  - Publications: These publications appear in chronological order, 1920-1966.
    - Publications, "An experimental study of visual movement and the phi-phenomenon."Am. J. Psychol. 1920, 31, 317-332.; 1920-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "A note on Henning's smell series." Am. J. Psychol. 1922, 33, 423-425. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "An experimental study of auditory tied-images." Am. J. Psychol. 1923, 34, 85-89. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ...with Conklin, V. "An experimental study of fear."Am. J. Psychol. 1925, 36, 96-101. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "The series of blacks, grays, and whites." Psycholog. R. 1925, 32, 334-336. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ...with Scahill, H.G. "Visual perception of movement."Am. J. Psychol. 1925, 36, 412-417. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "The 'Visual Perception' of Movement vx. the 'Apprehension' of Movement from Visual Stimuli."Am. J. Psychol. 1926, 37, 461-463. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "The investigation of the olfactory qualities."Psycholog. R. 1927, 34, 321-335. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Publications, ...with DeGowin, E.L. The tactual perception of simple geometrical forms." J. Gen. Psychol. 1928, 1, 114-122.; 1928-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "A reinterpretation of the color pyramid." Psycholog. R. 1929, 36, 83-90. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ...with Holt, C.R. "Gray and the color pyramid." Am. J. Psychol. 1929, 41, 284-290. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ...with Sanders, R.W. "Some conditions of the perception of visible movement."Am. J. Psychol. 1929, 41, 607-616. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Some new auditory apparatus." Am. J. Psychol. 1929, 41, 650-652 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ...with Karl, J.C. "The effect of the exposure time upon the R.L. of visible motion."JEPs 1930, 13, 365-369. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "An accurate differential color mixer." Am. J. Psychol. 1932, 44, 798-799. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "A simple campimeter."Am. J. Psychol. 1933, 45, 148. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Publications, "The dependence of auditory experience upon wave amplitude."Am. J. Psychol. 1933, 45, 463-470.; 1933-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ...with McMichael, George. "The psychophysical determination of the limits of pure gray." Am. J. Psychol. 1933, 45, 313-314. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ...with Gaylord, E. "The dependence of auditory localization with pitch." JEPs 1934, 17, 593-599. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Color nomenclature and specification." Psycholog. Bul. vol. 35, #8 October 1938. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ...with Hubbard, Margaret R. "The spectral location of psychologically unique yellow, green, and blue."Am. J. Psychol. 1939, 52, 242-254. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ...with Hubbard, Margaret R. "The spectral components of psychologically unique red." Am. J. Psychol. 1939, 52, 348-353. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ...with Ludlow, N. and Whiteman, A. "A study of 'Experimental Neurosis' in cats." J. Comp. Psychol. 1939, 28, 29-43. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ...with Olson, Ruth M. "The intensive difference limen in audition." JOSA 1941, 12, 517-525. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Publications, "Methodology in test preparation."JOSA 1943, 33, 308-315.; 1944-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "A color aptitude test developed for textiles."Textile World, 1944, 94, 84. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "A test of color aptitude."Textile Colorist & Converter, 1945, 67, 114F, 154. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "A color aptitude test, 1940 edition." J. Ap. Psychol. 1946, 30, 10-22. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Perception." Encyclopedia of Psychology, Edited by P. L. Harriman, Philos. Library, New York 1946. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Color."Foundations of Psychology. Boring, Langfeld, and Weld. Wiley 1948. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - ...with Smith, Stanley W. "The facilitative effect of red light on dark adaptation."JOSA 1953, 43, 541. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Publications, ...with Katz, Milton S. and Morris, Ailene. "Effets de durées variables d'adaptation au rouge sur une adaptation ultérieure a l'obscurité." Annales d'Optique Oculaire. t 3, No. 3, Mai 1954.; 1954-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Factors in the application of the Color Aptitude Test. Official Digest, Dec. 1954. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - ...with Smith, Stanley W. and Morris, Ailene. "Effects of exposure ot various red lights upon subsequent dark adaptation measured by the method of constant stimuli."JOSA 1955, 45, 502-506. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Specifications and calibration of the 1953 edition of the ISCC Color Aptitude Test."JOSA 1956, 46, 389-393. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A study of stability of discrimination in a visual matching test. Proc. of the XV International Congress of Psychology, 1957. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - ...with Thomas, F. and Luria, S.M. "A study of binocular color mixture." MRL Report No. 361, Sept. 1961 (Vision Research, Vol. 1, 108-120, 1961. ). (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Color Specification Based on Just Noticeable Differences of Hue. Tagungsband Luzern 1965. (Abstract in German, French, and English, paper in English) Oxford, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - --, Vision Research, Vol. 5, pp. 679-694. (Abstract in English, French, German, and Russian at the end of paper). (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - --, in Color Engineering, Chromatic Publ. Col, N.Y., N.Y. Vol. 4, #1, January-February 1966. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sistema di specifiche cromatiche a quattro colori principali basate sulle differenze di tono appena percepibili. Atti della fondazione Georgio Ronchi, Anno XXI, N.1, Feb. 1966, p. 11-26. (This paper relates to a lecture present at the International Color Meeting in Lucerne, Switzerland, June 1965 ). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publications he wrote and edited while being head of the Vision Branch of the U.S. Navy Submarine Base, 1947-1963.
    - Publications, "Standards for General Purpose Sun Glasses." D. Farnsworth. MRL #17 Sept. 10, 1948; 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Relative efficiency of goggles for dark adaptation." Z.J. Schoen & F.L. Dimmick. MRL #130 Apr. 9, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Checkerboard visual acuity targets: an experimental validation." F.L.D. & L.M. Rudolph. MRL #141 Dec. 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The effect of low color temperature illumination and red illumination upon subsequent dark adaptation." R.T. Mitchell. MRL# 146 Aug. 5, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Mapping the central scotomo of the dard adapted reine: comparison of a moving stimulus with a stationary presentation." L.S. McaMartin & F.L.D. MRL# 150 Nov. 1, 1949. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Visual acuity at scotopic levels of illumination." A. Morris & F.L.D. MRL# 162 Dec. 4, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The relation of dark adaptation to duration of prior red adaptation." R.T. Mitchell, A. Morris & F.L.D. MRL# 166 Dec. 6, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "An ophthalmological study of visual acuity under dim illumination." C. Pratt & F.L.D. MRL# 173 Jun. 6, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The parameters of scotopic sensitivity: (1) the effect of size." Jo Ann Smith & F.L.D. MRL# 174 Jun. 20, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Visual acuity tasks in a submarine." F.L.D. & Dean Farnsworth. MRL# 178 Oct. 10, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Factors in night vision sensitivity: the effect of brightness." S.G. deGroot, J.M. Dodge & Jo Ann Smith. MRL# 194 Mr. 18, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The facilitative effect of red light on dark adaptation."JOSA 43, 541, June 1953. S.W. Smith & F.L.D. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Factors in night vision sensitivity: III. The interrelation of size, brightness, and location." S.G. deGroot, J.M. Dodge & J.A. Smith. MRL# 234 Sept. 14, 1953. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The effect of refractive error on acuity through binoculars." J.A.S. Kinney and C.H. Pratt. MRL# 245 Apr. 12, 1954. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Effect of various durations of red adaptation on the course of subsequent dark adaptation." M.S. Katz, A. Morris, & F.L.D. MRL# 246 Apr. 27, 1954. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Visual characteristics of the submarine population." I. Schwarz & N.E. Sandberg. MRL# 252 Jun. 21, 1954. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Pilot studies of a scotopic sensitivity test." G. Fooks, E.J. Sweeney, & F.L.D. MRL# 285 Jun. 14, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The calculation of relative energy on metameric matches." R.E. Wienke. MRL# 57-7 Aug. 16, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Vision acuity: The professional vs. the non-professional." I. Schwartz. MRL# 57-10 Dec. 10, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Evaluation of omnitrainer (Visual training device)." I. Schwartz. MRL# 58-7 Apr. 15, 1958. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Measurement of the light adaptation of the rods." JOSA 47, 391, May 1957. S.W. Smith & F.L.D. MRL# 296 May 8, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "How red is red?Am. J. Psychol. LXXI, 298, mar. 1958. F.L.D. & R.E. Wienke. MRL# 303 Oct. 18, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Comparison of high acuity scores on Snellen and Ortho-rater tests." I. Schwartz & F.L.D. MRL# 304 Oct. 20, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Report on a direct-current high-pressure Xenon arc." R.E. Wienke MRL# 58-8 Nov. 6, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Standardizaton of a scotopic sensitivity test." E.J. Sweeney, J.A.S. Kinney & A.P. Ryan MRL# 308 Mar. 17, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Survey of the lighting installation in the U.S.S. Tusk (SS-426)." I. Schwartz & S.M. Luria. MRL# 59-3 Jun. 2, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Effect of the test stimulus on the measurement of dark adaptation." JOSA 49, 667, July 1959. E.J. Sweeney. MRL# 318 Sep. 8, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Nature of the limit of the color zone in perimetry." JOSA 49, 764, Aug. 1959. P.A. Kelsey & I. Schwartz. MRL# 324 Oct. 20, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Visual acuity under red vs. white illumination." S.M. Luria & I. Schwartz. MRL# 326 Jan. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Recommendations for minimal red light levels on board submarines." F.L.D. MRL# 60-2 Jan. 14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Multiple checkerboard acuity tester. I. Schwartz & S.M. Luria. MRL# 60-3 Jan. 18, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Underwater visual communication." F.L.D. & Jo Ann S. Kinney MRL# 60-5 Feb. 16, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Absolute threshhold for extremely wide fields." JOSA 48, 884, Dec. 1958. SlM. Luria. MRL# 331 Mar. 15, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Red lighting survey aboard the USS Randolph (CVS-15)." F.L.D., S.M. Luria, & I. Schwartz. MRL# 60-6 Apr. 6, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The interruption of dark adaptation." S.M. Luria & Jo Ann S. Kinney. MRL# 347 Feb. 1, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Accommodation and scotopic acuity." JOSA 51, 214, Feb. 1961. S.M. Luria MRL# 352 Apr. 20, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting survey of the U.S.S. Becuna (319). F.L.D., M. Siegel, & M. Connors. MRL# 61-4 May 8, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "A study of binocular color mixture." Vision Research, Vol. 1, Nos. 1/2 108-120, June 1961. T. Thomas, F.L.D. & S.M. Luria. MRL# 361 Sep. 20, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Shape of the red and green color zone gradients." JOSA 51, 874-877, Aug. 1961. Mary Connors & Patricia A. Kelsey MRL# 363 Oct. 5, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Relative red-green sensitivity as a function of retinal position."JOSA 52, 81-84, Jan. 1962. Marry Connors & Jo Ann S. Kinney MRL# 377 Feb. 28, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Discrimination of color. I. Comparison of three psycholophysical methods. II. Sensitivity as a function of spectral wavelength, 510-630 m." JOSA 52, 1067-1074, Sept. 1962. M.H. Siegel & F.L.D. MRL# 389 Oct. 30, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting Survey of U.S.S. Tringa (ASR-16)." J.A.S. Kinney & S.M. Luria MRL# 63-1 March 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting Survey on (sic.) U.S.S. Irex (ss4820)." S.M. Luria. MRL# 62-2 March 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting Survey of U.S.S. Angler (SS240)." J.A.S. Kinney & M.M. Conners. MRL# 63-5 Apr. 23, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Factors affecting induced color." Vision Research. Vol. 2, pp. 503-525, Pergamon Press, 1962 J.A.S. Kinney MRL# 400 Apr. 25, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Lighting Survey of U.S.S. Sablefish (ss303)." J.A.S. Kinney & M.M. connors. MRL# 63-7 May 8, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Night vision sensitivity during prolonged restriction from sunlight."J. Ap. Psychol. 1963 vol. 47, #1, pp. 65-67. J.A.S. Kinney. MRL# 401 May 21, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting Survey of U.S.S. Sea Robin (SS407)." M.M. Connors & K. Laxar. MRL# 63-9 Jun. 17, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting Survey of U.S.S. Sunbird (ASR-15)." M.M. Connors. MRL# 63-11 Aug. 26, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Discrimination of Color. III. Effect of spectral bandwidth."JOSA, vol. 53, no. 7, pp. 874-877, 1963. M.H. Siegel. MRL# 410 Sept. 9, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Lighting Survey of U.S.S. Hardhead (SS365)." M.M. Connors. MRL# 63-12 Nov. 1, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Effect of body position on meridional variations in scotopic acuity."Am. J. Psychol., vol. LXXVI, pp. 598-606, 1963. P.R. Kent. MRL# 64-2 May 6, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "A review of the rationale of the visual standards for submarine duty." P.R. Kent MRL# 428 May 19, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Reaction time under three viewing conditions: binocular, dominant eye, and non-dominant eye." JEPS, vol. 67, #3, 1964. P.K. Minucci & M.M. Connors. MRL# 430 May 22, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Effect of surround and stimulus luminance on the discrimination of hue." JOSA, vol. 54, #5, pp. 693-695, May 1964. M.M. Connors MRL# 435 Jul. 20, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Discrimination of Color. IV. Sensitivity as a function of spectral vavelength."JOSA, vol. 54, #6, pp. 821-823, June 1964. M.H. Siegel. MRL# 436 Jul. 31, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Book Reviews. Mostly published in the American Journal of Psychology., 1925-1961
    - Book Reviews (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes, Discussions, Lectures, 1 galley proof
    - Notes and Discussions (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Galley Proof: A Color Aptitude Test (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lectures given c. 1937-1938.Elementary Psychology. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Symposia and Congresses
    - Symposia and congresses (proceedings et al. of same) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A symposium on Color Tolerance. 8th Annual meeting of the Inter-Society Color Council. July 1939 Sponsored by The American Psychology Association. Reprinted from the American Journal of Psychology. Introduction to the meeting given by F.L. Dimmick. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A symposium on Color Blindness. Arranged by the Inter-Society Color Council for the March 1943 meeting of the Optical Society of America. Includes article by F.L.D. on Methodology in Test-Preparation. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Colour Vision Conference, Cambridge 1947. comments by F.L.D. Published in Documenta Ophthalmologica. Vol. III (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Proceedings of the 14th International Congress of Psychology, Montreal, June 1954. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Color Symposium held at the IES national Technical Conference in Miami Beach, Florida, August 31, 1964. Three invited papers. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A Paper by John W. Ward given at the International Colour Meeting in Lucerne, Switzerland, June 1965. Color Instrumentation for Industry. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A paper given at the Western Coatings Symposium, February 1966. Color Instruments take the visual Color Aptitude Test. This includes an attached letter to Dimmick relating to this paper. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Attributes of Colour perception. Reports from international scientific discussions held in Stockholm, June 6-8, 1966. Contains a photo of Dimmick on p. 30. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Recent Developments in Vision Research. National Academy of Sciences. Publication 1272, Washington, D.C., 1966. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Renshaw Vision Conference, May 17-18, 1967. Institute for Research Vision, The Ohio State University. (Dimmick attended). This title contains only the program and list of attendees. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Report on the 16th Session of the International Commission on Illumination, June 19-28, 1967. Published by U.S. Department of Commerce. Dimmick was advisor. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - List of contributors to various meetings, membership lists. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Unpublished Papers.
    - Several versions of a paper delivered at the Eastern Psychology Association at Bryn Mawr, 1939 (applies Bridgeman's theory to psychology, i.e. Bridgeman, Philosophy of Physics.) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Galley proofs to The Investigation of the Olfactory Qualities. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Two versions of Color Discrimination and the Testing of Color Aptitude. Paper given 1953 at Oxford. 27 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Factors in the application of the Color Aptitude Test. 10 pp. with graphs and annotations. later on published in "Official Digest," December 1954, Federation of Paint and Varnish Club Production. 20 pp. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Test results, parts of the paper, An Equal Hue System of Color Specifications. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Color Specifications based on Just Noticeable Differences of Hue. Several typewritten copies, some with notes, some with annotations, graphs and test results attached. (Box 1, Folder 17 & 18)
    - Typewritten copy of 'Visual Perception' of Movement, with revision notes by Titchener. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Paper (typewritten and handwritten manuscript) given after 1963. No title. Subject: metamer (i.e. the same color is produced by two stimuli); another folder re metamer is in the collection. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - A typewritten talk with no date. Probably early. "As a psychologist..." 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series II. Publications by fellow researchers covering a wide area of subjects, i.e. psychology, color vision, night vision, color theory, 1930-1968
  - Publications in chronological order, 1930-1968.
    - In chronological order (1930-1968) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publications he reviewed for the Biological Sciences Communications Project.
    - Papers reviewed for same. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Technical reports from the Department of the Navy. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Monographs
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell.The Stereoscope and Stereoscopic Photographs. Underwood & Underwood, New York, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Examiner's Guide for Psychological Examining in the Army. G.P.O. Washington, 1918. (Confidential publication). (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The Psycholoogical Laboratory of Cornell University. Oliver B. Wood, Worcester, 1900. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Butterfield, General Daniel. Address delivered on Founder's Day, January 11, 1898, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Le Grand, Yves. Vision Lumière et éclairage. Paris, Editions de la Revue Optique. 1958. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Age of Reason, Color Systems, Color Standards: The American Colorist by Faber Birren. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Three manuals on color prepared by Martin Marietta Company. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Solving the Color Problem, published by Procelain Enamel & Manufacturing Co. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Color Tree, published by Interchem. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Come Catch a Rainbow, published by Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Color and the Use of Color, published by the Illuminating Engineering Society. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Appendix to the Questionnaire, published by the Committee on Color Terminology. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Jacobson, Egbert. The Color Harmony Manual and How to Use It. CCA, Chicago, 1948. 13 vols. Boxed. (Box 2, 12)
    - Munsell Book of Color. Defining, Explaining and Illustrating the Fundamental Characteristics of Color. A Revision and Extension of 'The Atlas of the Munsell Color System' by A. H. Munsell Color Co., Baltimore, 1929. Abridged edition. Boxed (Box 2, 13)
    - Nagel, W. Tafeln zur Untersuchung des Farbenunterscheidungs Vermoegens. Bergmann Verlag, Wiesbaden, 1917. (Box 2, 14)
    - American Optical Company. Pseudo-Isochromatic Plates for Testing Color Perception. Beck Engraving Co., Philadelphia, 1917. (Box 2, 15)
    - Same as #15-revised edition. (Box 2, 16)
    - Descriptive Color Names Dictionary. Published by Container Corporation of America. 1950. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series III. CAT (Color Aptitude Test) and C.I.E. (Commission International Éclairage) research items